<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Primitive ordination and succession of bishops, deacons, pastors, and teachers in the church of Christ by George Fox.</title>
            <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 83KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 26 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B23139</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11304826_47377</idno>
  <idno type="VID">47377</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2264179563</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing F1885</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R30375</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">11304826</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B23139)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 47377)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1188:26 or 1461:8)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Primitive ordination and succession of bishops, deacons, pastors, and teachers in the church of Christ by George Fox.</title>
                  <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>50 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London?] printed :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1675.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>This work appears on reel 1188:26 and 1461:8.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of originals in the Harvard University Library and the Union Theological Seminary Library, New York.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Society of Friends --  Doctrines.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Apostolic succession.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Ordination (Canon law)</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-12 </date>
            <label>Alexis (Ali) Jakobson </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-12 </date>
            <label>Alexis (Ali) Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:47377:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:47377:1"/>
            <p>PRIMITIVE ORDINATION AND SUCCESSION, OF <hi>BISHOPS, DEACONS, PA<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>STORS and TEACHERS in the CHƲRCH of</hi> CHRIST.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>By</hi> George Fox.</p>
            <q>As thou sentest me into the World, even so also send I them into the World; they are not of the World, even as I am not of the World, <bibl>
                  <hi>John 17.</hi>
               </bibl>
            </q>
            <q>Ye shall know that I am in my Father, and you in me, and I in you, <bibl>
                  <hi>John 14.20.</hi>
               </bibl>
            </q>
            <q>I in them, and thou in me, <bibl>
                  <hi>John 17.</hi>
               </bibl>
            </q>
            <q>Go and teach all Nations, I will be with you to the End of the World, <bibl>
                  <hi>Mat. 28.</hi>
               </bibl>
            </q>
            <q>Go ye into all the World, and preach the Gospel, <bibl>
                  <hi>Mark 16.</hi>
               </bibl>
            </q>
            <q>Examine your selves whether you be in the Faith, prove your own selves, know ye not your own selves, how that Jesus Christ is in you, except ye be Reprobates, <bibl>
                  <hi>2 Cor. 13.5,</hi>
               </bibl>
            </q>
            <p>Printed in the Year 1675.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="argument">
            <pb facs="tcp:47377:2"/>
            <p>How Christ ordained his Twelve Apostles, and Seventy Disciples.</p>
            <p>How he would be with them to the End of the World, and in them.</p>
            <p>What was the Maintenance he ordained for them.</p>
            <p>How Christ chose and ordained Pastors, Teachers, Prophets, and Evangelists in the Church.</p>
            <p>And the Primitive Ordination of Bishops, and Deacons, and Elders in the Church.</p>
            <p>Also who they are that do succeed them in their Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dination, Succession, Possession, Doctrine and Practice, in their Preaching, Praying, Singing and Mainte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance, and who not.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:47377:2"/>
            <head>CONCERNING Ordination AND Succession. <hi>About which there is so much Discourse and Work in all</hi> Christendom.</head>
            <p>LEave off all your Busling, and come to Christ and his Apostles, and see how they were or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dained and sent forth; Christ saith in <hi>Mat.</hi> 28. <hi>Go therefore, and teach all Nations, &amp;c.</hi> Now here was the Command of Christ, after he was risen: So these were not to sit down in Benefices, but they were to go and teach all Nations; the Nation of <hi>Esau,</hi> and the <hi>Egyptians, Hams</hi> and <hi>Tartars, Barba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rians, Scythians, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>These did not reason, What shall I do with my Wife and Children; or how shall I do for a main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenance; so as Christ commanded them to go and teach all Nations? here was the Love of God and Christ to all the World: And again <hi>Mark</hi> 16. Christ said unto his Disciples, <hi>Go ye into all the World, and preach the Gospel to every Creature;</hi> mark, to every Creature the Gospel of Salvation was to be
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:47377:3"/>preached; here Christ makes no Sects, nor leaves out some Part of the World; but as he tasted Death for every man, and was an Offering for the Sins of the whole World, so he sent his Disciples, which he ordained to preach the Gospel, into all Nations; and he saith, <hi>Lo I am with you alwayes, even to the End of the World;</hi> and Christ sayes, <hi>If you were of the World, the World would love its own, but because you are not of the World, but I have chosen you out of the World, therefore the World hates you:</hi> So these were the chosen Disciples of Christ, which he sent forth into the World, <hi>Joh.</hi> 15. And Christ saith, <hi>I have given them the Words which thou gavest me, and they have received them, and have known surely that I came out from thee, they have believed that thou didst send me,</hi> Joh. 17. <hi>and the Glory thou gavest me, I have gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven them, and that they may be one, even as we are one, I in them, and they in me, that they may be made perfect in one.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>So here you may see, that Christ is in his Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles, that he sends forth into all Nations, and he will send them his Comforter, which shall lead them into all Truth, who is the Spirit of Truth, and this Comforter will teach you all things, saith Christ, and bring all things to your Remembrance, whatsoever I have said to you, <hi>Joh.</hi> 13. And fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Christ saith, Joh. 25. <hi>I have chosen you and or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dained you, that you should go and bring forth Fruit, and that your Fruits should remain, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>So here you may see how Christ chose and or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dained his ministers, and how he would be with them, and in them, and how he had chosen them
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:47377:3"/>out of the World, and they were not of the World, as he was not of the World, and therefore the World did hate these that were chosen &amp; ordained, and sent forth by Christ, and were not like a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pany of Worldlings, seeking for great fat Benefices and to agree with Nations or Countries for so much a Year, and to hale People into Courts, and cast them into Prison, if they would not give them main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenance or earthly things.</p>
            <p>And when Christ sent forth his seventy Disciples by two and two into every City, and Town, and Place, as in <hi>Luke</hi> 10. he said to them, <hi>Go your Wayes, behold, I send you forth as Lambs among Wolves</hi> (so here is Christ's Sending and Command) <hi>carry nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Purse, nor Scrip, nor Shoes, and salute no Man by the Way, and into what House ye enter, first say, Peace be unto this House, &amp;c. and in the same House remain eating and drinking such Things as they set before you; for the Workman is worthy of his Meat, &amp;c. and into what City ye enter, and they receive you, eat such things as they set before you:</hi> And when those seventy re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turned again to Christ, &amp;c. in the same Hour Jesus rejoyced in Spirit and said, <hi>I thank thee O Father, Lord of Heaven and Earth, that thou hast hid these Things from the wise and prudent, and hast revealed them unto Babes, even so Father, &amp;c. And no Man knoweth who the Son is, but the Father, and who the Father is, but the Son, and him to whom the Son will reveal him:</hi> And Jesus said privily to his Disciples, <hi>Blessed are the Eyes which see these Things.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>So here you may see how Christ sent forth his se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venty Disciples, and how he thanked his Father,
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:47377:4"/>which had reveal'd him &amp; these things unto Babes; and how the Son had revealed these things unto his Disciples; so these did Christ chuse and ordain, and they went forth in the Revelation of the Son: And likewise, when Christ had sent forth his twelve Dis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciples before, he said to them, <hi>As ye go, preach, say<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, the Kingdom of Heaven is at Hand, &amp;c. and free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly you have received, freely give, provide neither Gold, nor Silver, nor Brass in your Purses, no Scrips for your Journey, nor Staffs, nor two Coats, nor Shoes for your Journey, &amp;c. and into whatsoever City or Town ye shall enter, enquire who is worthy, and there abide till ye go thence, &amp;c. And whosoever will not receive you, nor hear your Words, when you depart out of that House or City, shake off the Dust of your Feet, &amp;c.</hi> So these were not to agree for a Benefice with the Heads of the Town, and if they would not pay them, then cast them into Prison.</p>
            <p>And also ye may see the same Ordination and sending forth of Christ's ministers in <hi>Mark</hi> 6. and mark, whosoever would not hear Christ's Apostles and Disciples Preaching, they were to shake the Dust off their Feet against them, they were not to summon them to Courts, and cast them into Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>son, because they would not hear them; for sayes Christ, <hi>He that heareth you, heareth me, and he that despiseth you, despiseth me, and he that despiseth me, despiseth him that sent me,</hi> Luke 10. And Christ saith in <hi>Luke</hi> 22.35. unto his Disciples, <hi>When I sent you without Purse, Scrip and Shoes, lacked you any Thing?</hi> and they said <hi>Nay.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now you may plainly see here Christ's mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sters,
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:47377:4"/>both before he was crucified and after, when he was risen, the manner of Christ's ordaining and choosing and sending forth his ministers; and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore he was crucified, he ask'd his ministers that he did send forth freely, whether they lacked for any thing, and their Answer was to Christ, they wanted nothing.</p>
            <p>Now try your selves you ministers in our Dayes by Christ's Words and his ministers then, who are sent forth in the Wills of men, whether ye can give the same Answer, that ye want for nothing, and that you go forth freely, as they did? And Christ saith, <hi>I will be with you, and I will be within you;</hi> now they that follow the Apostles in their Succes<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sion, they must be in the same Power and Holy Ghost that the Apostles were in, and not to succeed them in the Form, as the false Prophets did the true, and Anti-christ doth the true Christ, who got the true Christ's Words; but to succeed the Apostles in the same Holy Ghost, and Power, and Life that they were in, that is the right Succession, and so in their Inheritance and possession; for any worldly man will tell you, it signifies nothing to have only the Writings of an Estate, and not to possess it: And therefore to succeed the Apostles aright, is to succeed them in the same power and holy Ghost they were in, and to have Christ with them and in them; for Christ saith, <hi>Matth.</hi> 21.16. <hi>Out of the Mouthes of Babes and Sucklings hast thou ordained Strength;</hi> and <hi>Psal.</hi> 8.</p>
            <p>So you may see here how Christ ordained Babes and Sucklings to preach his Name freely, as they
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:47377:5"/>had received freely; and you know the Babes and Sucklings are not fit to be sent to Schools, but these were taught of Christ, and ordained of him to speak and to confess Christ Jesus freely, as they had re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived; and he ordain'd Strength out of the mouthes of these Babes and Sucklings; yea, such Strength, as the Devil, nor all his ministers, nor all the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fessors of the World were able to gainsay, but it convinced the Gainsayers; so they need not lye at Schools many Years, whom Christ ordains and sends forth: And when they chose another Disci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple in the room of <hi>Judas,</hi> to be a Witness with the Apostles of Christ's Resurrection, the Lord gave them <hi>Matthias</hi> by Lot; see <hi>Acts</hi> 1. And the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stle <hi>Paul</hi> saith in <hi>Ephes.</hi> 3.7. <hi>How that by Revelation he had made known to him the Mystery whereof he was made a Minister, according to the Gift of Grace of God given to him by the effectual Working of his Power.</hi> And again the Apostle saith, <hi>That the Gospel which was preached to every Creature under Heaven, whereof I Paul am made a Minister, according to the Dispensation of God, which was given unto me, which hath been hid from Ages and Generations, but now is manifested to his Saints, &amp;c. which Mystery is Christ in you, the Hope of Glory, whom we preach</hi> (to wit, the Apostles and mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nisters of Christ) <hi>warning every man, and teaching every Man in all Wisdom, that we may present every man perfect in Christ Jesus.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Here you may see <hi>Paul</hi>'s Ordination, and how he and the Apostles received their ministry, and what he preach'd, <hi>Col.</hi> 18. And again the Apostle saith, <hi>When Christ ascended up on high, he led Captivity cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tive,
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:47377:5"/>and gave Gifts unto Men, and he gave some Ape<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles, some Prophets, some Evangelists and some Pastors, and Teachers, for the perfecting of the Saints, for the Work of the Ministry, for the edifying of the Body of Christ:</hi> So this Gift of Christ made them ministers and you that deny perfection, deny the Work of Christ's ministers, as you may see <hi>Ephes.</hi> 4. And the Apostle sayes, <hi>We speak the Wisdom of God in a Mystery, even the hidden Wisdom of God, ordained be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the World to our Glory:</hi> So here you may see what he preached, 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 2.6. And in <hi>Gal.</hi> 1. Paul <hi>an Apostle, not of man, nor by man, but by Jesus Christ, and God the Father, who raised him from the Dead. I certifie you Brethren, that the Gospel which is preached, by me, is not after man; for I neither received it of man, neither was I taught it, but by the Revelation of Jesus Christ.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>So here you may see how the Apostle was or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dained, and from whom he received his Gospel and what he preach'd, and how that he was an A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>postle, not of man nor by man: and the Gospel which he preached was not after man; and the Apostle saith in <hi>Acts</hi> 10.42. <hi>he hath commanded us</hi> (to wit Christ) <hi>to preach unto the people, and to testifie that it was he, which was ordained of God to be the Judge of Quick &amp; Dead:</hi> Here you may see it was Christ that commanded his ministers and his Disciples to preach; and in <hi>Mark</hi> 3. He ordained twelve that they should be with him that he might send them forth to preach; mark, here is Christ's Ordination and his sending forth.</p>
            <p>So all along you may see how Christ ordained
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:47377:6"/>his ministers and Disciples, and the seventy, and his Pastors, Prophets, Evangelists and Teachers, and he will be with them to the End of the VVorld, and he will be in them, and they shall be in him, and they shall have his holy Ghost to lead them into all Truth.</p>
            <p>Now here is a Possession, and they that do suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed them in the Possession must be such as possess Christ in them, and his holy Ghost, and the same Power and Spirit that the Apostles did possess; they must possess the same VVisdom which was ordained before the World was, and the same my<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stery hid from Ages and Generations, and the same Gift from him that is ascended up on high, and the same Gospel which is not after man, neither is it received of man nor by man; this they must possess if they be the Successors of the Apostles; for any false Prophet or Apostle, or messenger of Satan, An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tichrist or Wolves may get the Sheeps Cloathing, the outside, the Form of Godliness and deny the Power thereof, such are not the Successors of the Apostles in their Inheritance and Possession.</p>
            <p>Now the Apostles in this Possession they that did succeed them in it were called Elders, and they ordained Decrees by the holy Ghost, as in <hi>Acts</hi> 16. to the Churches that were established in the Faith: &amp; they ordained Elders in every Church; they that were in the Possession of the holy Ghost, ordained others that were in the holy Ghost. <hi>Acts</hi> 14. <hi>&amp;</hi> 20. Take heed therefore unto your selves, and unto all the Flock of God, over which the holy Ghost hath made you Overseers, to feed the Church of God
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:47377:6"/>which he hath purchased with his own Blood; mark here you may see the Ordination of Overseers or Elders, and what they were to oversee withal and feed withal, the holy Ghost.</p>
            <p>Now they that do succeed them in their Elder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ship or Oversight, their Succession must be in the Possession of the same holy Ghost, else they are no Successors of the Apostles, nor the Elders, nor O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verseers; but are in the Form of Godliness without the Power thereof, which are to be turned away from: And in 1 <hi>Pet.</hi> 5. He that is an Elder writes to the Elders, who was a Witness of the Sufferings of Christ, and also a Partaker of the Glory that should be revealed: <hi>Feed the Flock of God</hi> (saith he) <hi>which is amongst you, take the Oversight thereof, not by constraint but willingly, not for filthy Lucre but of a rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy Mind; neither as Lords over God's Heritage; but being Examples to the Flock.</hi> Now here you may see further of the Ordination of Elders, and the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sel of an Elder to them that were Partakers of the Glory, and Witnesses of the Sufferings of Christ, they should feed and take the Oversight willingly and not for filthy Lucre, not being Lords over God's Heritage; but Examples to the Flock. Now they that are as Lords, and are ill Examples, and will be overseers for filthy Lucre, are not Succeeders of the Apostles, neither in their Possession, nor Example, nor Command.</p>
            <p>So all they that say they have not the same Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, and holy Ghost the Apostles had, do not suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed the Apostles in their Possession, and all they who deny, that any People should expect the same
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:47377:7"/>Power and holy Ghost the Apostles had, deny their Possession, and are no Succeeders of them: And all they that deny the Light that shines in the Heart to give them the Knowledge of the Glory of God in the Face of Christ Jesus now adayes in People, and all they that deny the Anointing within to teach, and the Word of God in the Heart and mouth to obey and do, which was the Word of Faith the Apostle preached, they are not in the Succession of the Apostles, nor in the Doctrine that they preach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, nor in the Possession and Practicet they lived in.</p>
            <p>And all they that deny that there was not an Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fering for the Sins of the whole World, and that he doth not enlighten every man that cometh into the World, with the Light, which is the Life in the Word, and forbid People from believing in this Light, and say, that God doth not write his Law in Peoples hearts now, nor put it into their minds now; all such, I say, do not follow the Apostles in their Succession of their Life and Power they were in, for they have denyed their Doctrine, and that which all good Christians do possess.</p>
            <p>And all such as say, that the Grace of God hath not appeared to all men to teach them, and bring their Salvation and that the manifestation of the Spirit is not given to every man to profit withall, and that God doth not give his holy Ghost to them that rebelled against it, and that Christ hath not sent his holy Ghost to lead his ministers now into all Truth, which holy Ghost shall reprove the World of Sin, &amp;c. they that deny this are not the Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cessors of the Apostles, in their Possession of
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:47377:7"/>heir Life and Power in the holy Ghost; but are denyers of their Doctrine, though they may geta Form of Words, but deny the Power thereof; such are to be turned away from.</p>
            <p>So you may see how Christ hath ordained his mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nisters; for he himself was made after the order of <hi>Melchizedeck,</hi> and not after the Order of <hi>Aaron</hi> (though <hi>Aaron</hi> was made after an Order) and so they were ordained to offer Sacrifices, as in <hi>Heb.</hi> 7.8. which Priesthood Christ hath ended, and their Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, who ordained his Disciples and Elders as you may see before: and all that do succeed them must be in the same Grace, in the same Light and holy Ghost, and Power, and the same Law of Life, and of the Spirit, and the same Anointing within, and the same Word of Faith in the Heart and mouth, and the same Gift from Christ that is ascended up on high, and Christ within according to his Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mise, that he would dwell in them, and as the A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>postle saith, <hi>It pleased the Father to reveal his Son in me,</hi> and so he preached him in others: and all A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>postles, Pastors, Evangelists, Teachers, Elders, Overseers, &amp;c. that do not follow the Apostles in the Possession of this before mentioned, and are not Inheritors of this, then they must needs be Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>states, and do not follow the Apostles in the Pos<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>session and Practice, though they may get the Form and not in the same Power, but deny it; they are not the Succeeders of the Apostles; but are to be turned away from; for none do succeed the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles, Evangelists, and Pastors, Elders, Overseers, and Teachers, but who succeed them in Christ, and in the same Power and holy Ghost that they were in
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:47377:8"/>who gave forth the Scriptures: And in <hi>Acts</hi> 19.13. then certaine of the vagabond <hi>Jews</hi> Exorcists, took upon them to call over them which had evil Spirits in the Name of the Lord Jesus, saying, <hi>we adjure you by Jesus whom Paul preacheth,</hi> and there were seven Sons of one <hi>Sceva</hi> a Jew and chief of the Priests, which did so, and the evil Spirit answered and said, <hi>Jesus I know, and Paul I know, but who are yee? And the man in whom the evil Spirit was, leaped on them and overcame them, and prevailed against them so that they fled out of the House, naked and wounded, and this was known to all the</hi> Jews <hi>and</hi> Greeks <hi>also dwelling at</hi> E phesus, <hi>and Fear fell on them all and the Name of the Lord Iesus was magnified, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now it is clear that those did not succeed in the Ordination of the Apostles, in the Possession of their Power, Life and holy Ghost, though they had the Form of Words, and used the Name of the Lord Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sus Christ: And you may clearly see, that it is not the saying the Form of Christ's and the Apostles words, and such as can hold them in their memories, that doth not bring them to succeed the Apostles, and so to plead their Ordination, because they can speak Christ's and the Apostles Words, this doth not prove their Succession in the Ordination of Christ nor the Apostles; for it sayes, they fled away naked, they wanted the Power and holy Ghost the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles were in: and so are not all naked though they have the Form of Christ's and the Apostles words, as these were? Let them be Priests or Professors, if they be not in the same holy Ghost, and Power the Apostles were in; they are naked.</p>
            <p>And may not this be an Example to all Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stendom
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:47377:8"/>to take heed how they use the Form of Christ's and the Apostles Words, without they be in the same Fear of God, and Power, and holy Ghost the Apostles were in: So its clear, none do succeed the Apostles in the same Ordination and Succession, but such as do succeed them in the same Power and holy Ghost, the Apostles were in; for can naked men, with the Form of Christ's and the Apostles Words, convert any men or women to Christ or God? that be not in the same Power and holy Ghost the Apostles were in, which Power cloathes them: And are not all naked men liable to be wounded by the evil Spirit? and flee frour the evil wounded, like these Priests Sons, that are not in the same Power and holy Ghost the Apostles were in: and therefore is not this a fearfull warning to all Christendom, to take heed how they take upon them, or use any way the Form of Christs or the Apostles Words, without being in the same Life and Power, and holy Ghost the Apostles were in, lest the evil Spirit get power over them, as it did over this Priest and his seven Sons.</p>
            <p>And are not all Vagabonds from the Apostles power and Inheritance, that are not in the same power and holy Ghost the Apostles were in, though they may talk and have the Form of Christ's and the Apostles Words, as common Vagabonds and Wanderers may talk of other mens Possessions: and did <hi>Simon Magus</hi> continue in the Succession of the Apostles, though he was convinced? And did not he go out of the Succession of the Apostles, when he thought the Gift of God was to be purchased
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:47377:9"/>with money? did not <hi>Peter</hi> tell him, he was in the Gall of Bitterness, and Bond of Iniquity, though he was a professor of Christ, and a Believer as ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry are now? so you may see, that he did not suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed the Apostles in the Life, and holy Ghost, and Power, and you may clearly see the Succession to the Apostles is in the Life, and Power, and holy Ghost that they were in.</p>
            <p>And do not you think that there are many <hi>Si<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Magus</hi> now adayes, in Christendom, in their Gall of Bitterness, and Bond of Iniquity, that think the Gift of God can be bought and fold for money? And are there not many now adayes, that do buy and sell the Gospel, as they call it, to people for money? And you cannot say, that these succeed the Apostles in their possession in the Life and pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er; but <hi>Simon Magus</hi> in his Gall of Bitterness and Bond of Iniquity.</p>
            <p>And do you think, <hi>Diotrephes,</hi> that <hi>John</hi> reproves followed the Apostle with his prating, in the pos<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>session, and in the Succession of the power and ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Ghost as in the third Epistle of <hi>John.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And the Apostle saith 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 4.19. <hi>But I will come to you shortly, if the Lord will, and we will know not the Speech of them that are puft up; but the Power; for the Kingdom of God is not in Word, but in Power:</hi> So here it is clear, the Knowledge, Ordination, and Succession must be in the Power, and they that do succeed the Apostles, in their possession and Ordination in the Gospel, which is the power of God, they must be in the same Power of God, the Gospel, which brings Life and Immortality to
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:47377:9"/>Light; for all that have the Form of Godliness and deny the Power thereof, deny the Gospel, for the Gospel is the power of God: So they must succeed them in the possession of this power that brings Life and Immortality to Light, that shines over the Devil, that hath darkened them; for the Gospel, the Power of God, is called the everlasting Gospel, and there fore the Succession must be in the ever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lasting Gospel, and Power of God; and therefore to succeed them in the Form without the Power and holy Ghost is no Succession to the A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>postles in their Ordination; but a Succession of the false Apostles, that got the Form and denyed the Power, from such saith the Apostle (that was in the Succession of the Life and Power and Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation by Christ) turn away from such: And the Apostle saith 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 18. <hi>For the preaching of the Cross</hi> (to wit, of Christ) <hi>is to them that perish Foolish<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness; but unto us which are saved</hi> (to wit, the true Apostles and Christians) <hi>it is the Power of God.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now they that do succeed the Apostles, and true Christians in the Cross of Christ, it is in the Power of God that crucifies them from the World: it is not to succeed the Apostles with wooden, stone silver or brass Crosses; for these would have been foolish Things to the Apostles; for you cannot say, that you succeed the Apostles with your woo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den, stone, brass and silver Cross, except you say these your own Inventions of Stone, Wood, Brass, and other such like made outward Crosses are the Power of God.</p>
            <p>And the Apostle saith, we speak the Wisdom
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:47377:10"/>God in a Mystery, which Wisdom we speak among them that are perfect; yet not the Wisdom of this World nor of the Princes of this World, which cometh to nought: So all that do succeed the A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>postles in their Ordination and Succession, it must be in this Wisdom of God, which is pure and gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle from above, and easie to be intreated, it must be in the Possession of this Wisdom (which will abide and not come to naught) which they spoak amongst them that were perfect: And it is not to succeed the Apostles, to get Christ's and the Apostles Words to talk of them in Man's Wisdom that comes to naught: And the Apostle saith, <hi>my Speech was not with enticing Words of Man's Wisdom; but in the Demonstration of the Spirit, and of Power.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And now all Preachers that do succeed the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles, it must be in the same Demonstration of the Spirit and Power; for they do not succeed the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles, whose Speech and Preaching is only with the enticing Words of mans Wisdom: And the A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>postle saith, <hi>That your Faith should not stand in the Wisdom of men, but in the Power of God:</hi> So whose Faith doth stand in the Wisdom of men, and not in the same Power and Wisdom of God the Apostles were in, do not succeed the Apostles in their Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation and Succession: And the Apostle saith, <hi>God hath revealed unto us by his Spirit the deep Things of God, and we have not received the Spirit of the World, but the Spirit which is of God, that we might know the things that are freely given to us of God</hi> (mark, Freely) <hi>which things also we speak, not in the Words which man's
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:47377:10"/>VVisdom teacheth, but which the Holy Ghost teacheth, &amp;c.</hi> and saith he, <hi>we have the Mind of Christ.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>So now all that do succeed the Apostles, must be in the Spirit of God that reveals the deep things of God to them, and by which Spirit they know the deep Things of God, given forth freely unto them, that they may give them forth freely again to o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers, according to the Ordination and Command of Christ; and they must succeed them in the same Speech, not to speak the things of God in the Words which man's Wisdom doth teach, but in those Words which the Holy Ghost doth teach: And now they that speak the Words of Christ and the Apostles in man's Wisdom, and not freely, and have not the Mind of Christ, and deny the Spirit of Revelation, but speak the Apostles Words by the Spirit of the World, that knows not the Things of God, such do not follow the Apostles in their Succession of the Spirit of God, nor in their Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation by the Spirit of God: And likewise all such that teach for filthy Lucre, <hi>and serve not the Lord Jesus Christ, but their own Bellies,</hi> and are covetous Teachers, and are <hi>heady, high-minded, Lovers of Pleasures more then Lovers of God, and are Strikers, and Persecutors, and think that Gain is Godliness,</hi> all such do not follow the <hi>Apostles</hi> in their Succession and Ordination; for the <hi>Apostles</hi> declared against such, who freely as they had received, freely they were commanded to give, and did so; and them that follow not the Apostles in this their Example, and Christ in his Command, are not Followers and Succeeders to Christ and the Apostles, in the same
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:47377:11"/>Life, Power and Doctrine: Now for the Tryal of Bishops and Deacons, that follow the Apostles in their Succession; <hi>A Bishop must be blameless, the Husband of one Wife, vigilant, sober, of good Beha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viour, given to Hospitality, apt to teach, not given to Wine, no Striker, not greedy of filthy Lucre, but pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tient, not a Brawler, not covetous, one that can rule well his own House, having his Children in Subjection with all Gravity, not a Novice, lest he be lifted up with Pride, and fall into Condemnation of the Devil: More<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>over, he must have a good Report of them that are without lest he fall into Reproach, and the Snare of the Devil,</hi> 1 Tim. 3. And in <hi>Tit.</hi> 1. <hi>A Bishop must be blameless, as the Steward of God, not self-willed, nor soon angry, not given to Wine, no Striker, not given to filthy Lucre; but a Lover of Hospitality, a Lover of good Men sober, just, holy temperate, holding fast the Faithful Word, &amp;c. for there are many unruly and vain Talkers, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now here you may see the Ordination of Bishops; and if they do not succeed in these Steps and Pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cepts as the Apostles have laid down, they do not succeed the Apostles; for if he be of <hi>ill Behaviour, not given to Hospitality, nor apt to teach freely</hi> (as they did) <hi>and if he be given to Wine, and a Striker, and greedy of filthy Lucre, and not patient, but a Brawler, and Covetous, and not the Husband of one Wife, and can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not rule his own House well, and hath not his Children in Subjection and in Gravity, and is a Novice, and puft up in Pride, and hath an ill Report from them without, and self-willed, and soon angry, not sober, just, holy and temperate, &amp;c.</hi> Such follow not nor succeed not the Apostles in their Ordination and Succession, nor in
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:47377:11"/>their Life and Power of the holy Ghost, but were reproved by them: Now likewise concerning Dea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cons, <hi>if they be not grave, and if they be double-tongued, or given to much Wine, or if greedy of filthy Lucre, if their Wives be not grave and sober, but slanderous,</hi> they are such as do not follow the Apostles in their Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation and Succession; therefore the Apostle sayes, <hi>First they must be proved, and then let them use their Office of a Deacon, &amp;c. being found blameless:</hi> And likewise the Apostle saith, they must hold the My<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stery of Faith in a pure Conscience; mark, in a pure Conscience; and Faith is a Mystery; and therefore all such that are not qualified according to the Apostle's Direction to <hi>Timothy</hi> and <hi>Titas,</hi> do not follow and succeed the Apostles in their spiritu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al Succession and Ordination: And moreover, the Apostle saith, <hi>Follow us as we follow Christ, and walk as ye have us for an Example;</hi> and they coveted no man's Gold, nor Silver, nor Apparel, and said, <hi>Although he preached the Gospel, yet he had nothing to glory of; and what is my Reward?</hi> (sayes he) <hi>verily, that when I preach the Gospel, that I make the Gospel of Christ without Charge,</hi> 1 Cor. 9.</p>
            <p>And now you that do not follow the Apostle in these Things, both in Example and Life, and to keep the Gospel without Charge, you do not follow the Apostles in the spiritual Succession and Ordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, neither are you to be followed, but as you follow Christ, and the Example of the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles.</p>
            <p>And all such that forbid to marry, and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand to abstain from Meats, such are not the Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeders
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:47377:12"/>of the Apostles in their Ordination, and Possession of the Heavenly Power and Spirit; but such are Speakers of Lyes, and are such as are de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parted from the Faith, giving Heed to seducing Spirits, and Doctrine of Devils speaking Lyes in Hypocrisie, having their Consciences seared, as with an Hot Iron, 1 <hi>Tim.</hi> 4. And in <hi>Rom.</hi> 8. <hi>If the Spirit of him that raised up Jesus from the dead dweleth in you, he that raised up Jesus shall quicken your mortal Bodies by his Spirit that dwelleth in you: For as many is are lead by the Spirit of God are the Sons of God; but ye have received the Spirit of Adoption, whereby we cry</hi> Abba <hi>Father, which Spirit it self bear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth witness with our Spirits, that we are the Children of God; for the Law of the Spirit of Life in Christ Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sus hath made me free from the Law of Sin and Death,</hi> saith the Apostle.</p>
            <p>Now here was the Possession of the Apostles, and all true Christians, and all that follow them in their Succession, and heavenly Possession, must be led by the Spirit of God, and to have the same Spirit to bear witness with their Spirits, that they are the Sons of God; yea the same Spirit that rai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sed up Jesus from the dead, to dwell in them, and to quicken their mortall Bodies: So the Succes<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sion must be in this same Spirit, and in the Law of the Spirit of Life in Christ Jesus, which makes free from the Law of Sin and Death, and then there will be the Fruits of the Spirit to shew forth their Succession to the Apostles, that they do suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed them in the same Spirit, in the Law of the Spirit of Life that is in Christ Jesus, that doth
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:47377:12"/>make them free Men and Women from the Law of Sin and Death: So all the Succeeders of the A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>postles in the Spirit can cry <hi>Abba</hi> Father. And the Apostle saith in <hi>Rom.</hi> 10. <hi>How shall he preach except he be sent? &amp;c. And the Word is nigh thee in the Heart and Mouth, and this is the Word of Faith which we preach,</hi> which were sent (to wit, the A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>postles) to preach it.</p>
            <p>So all that do succeed the Apostles, they must be sent of Christ in the same Power and Spirit, that the Apostles were sent from God and Christ, and freely give as they have received from him free<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, and preach the same Word of Faith, which is nigh in Men and Women, even in their Mouthes and Hearts to obey it and do it; for if People go not in the same Power and Spirit as the Apostles were in, and preach the same, they are not succeed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers of them in their Possisseon. Now Christ said, <hi>I am come in my Father's Name and you received me not; if another shall come in his own Name, him you will receive, John</hi> 5.</p>
            <p>And now is it not clearly seen to this Day, that the Prophets and Apostles, that came in the Name of the Lord and of Christ, such were alwayes hated; and they would not receive them: And by sad Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perience we have found it in our Age, who have been moved by the Lord, and gone in the Name of the Lord to speak to Priests and Professors, many of which you have imprisoned and beat; but if a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny have come in their own Name, such are recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved by you.</p>
            <p>And if <hi>Paul</hi> had been an Apostle by Men, or of
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:47377:13"/>Men, or had received his Gospel and Ordination by Men or from Men, Men would not have called him <hi>a Ring-leader, and a pestilent Fellow, &amp;c.</hi> And the Apostle said, <hi>they were able Ministers of the new Testament, not of the Letter, but of the Spirit; for the Letter killeth, but the Spirit giveth Life.</hi> So all that follow the Apostles in their Ordination and Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cession, must be Ministers of the Spirit and of the new Testament, yea of the Spirit that giveth Life, and not of the Letter that killeth: Now they that are Ministers, but not of the same Spirit that gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veth Life, and of the new Testament that the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles were in, do not follow them in their Ordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion and Succession, though they may have the Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter. And the Apostle saith, <hi>We all with open Face, beholding as in a Glass the Glory of the Lord, are changed into the same Image from Glory to Glory, even by the Spirit of the Lord,</hi> 2 <hi>Cor.</hi> 3.13. <hi>And we having the same Spirit of Faith, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now here was the Apostles Possession, and all that follow them in their Possesison, Ordination, and Succesison, must behold the same Glory as they all did, and know the same changing from Glory to Glory, even by the Spirit of the Lord, and they must be in the same Spirit of Faith, else they do not follow the Apostles, and true Christians in their Ordination and Succession. And the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles saith, 2 <hi>Cor.</hi> 6. <hi>In all things approving our selves as the Ministers of God, in much Patience in Afflictions, in Necessities, in Distresses, in Stripes, in Imprisonments, in Tumults, in Labours, in Watchings, in Fastings, by Pureness, by Knowledge, by Long-Suffering, by
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:47377:13"/>Kindness, by the holy Ghost, by Love unfeign'd, by the Word of Truth, by the Power of God, by the Arm of Righ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teousness, &amp;c.</hi> Now all you that follow the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles in their Succession, you must approve your selves as the Ministers of Christ, by your Patience, by your Pureness, by your Long-Suffering, by Know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge, by Kindness, by Love unfeigned, by the Word of Truth, by the Power of God, by the Arm of Righteousness, and by the Holy Ghost: But now if you say, you have not the same holy Ghost as the Apostles had, then you cannot approve your selves, neither can you follow them in the same Ordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion and Succession as the Apostles were in: And you that be the Strikers, and Imprisoners, and Afflicters of People for Religion, you do not follow the Apostles in their Ordination and Succession that were stript, imprisoned and afflicted.</p>
            <p>And the Apostle saith, <hi>Ye are the Temples of the Living God; as God hath said, I will dwell in them and walk in them, and I will be their God and they shall be my People, and I will be a Father unto you and you shall be my Sons and Daughters, saith the Lord God Almighty:</hi> Now here was the Possession of the Apostles and true Church: Now all that follow the Apostles in their Ordination, and Succession, and Possession in the true Church, they must follow them in their Sonship and Daughtership, and must be such as God dwels in, and walks in, if not, and they will not have him to dwell in them and walk in them, and so be the Sons and Daughters of God, then they do not succeed the Apostles and true Church in their Possession: And the Apostle saith, <hi>Gal.</hi> 3. <hi>For ye
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:47377:14"/>are all the Children of God by Faith in Christ Jesus; for as many of you as have been baptized into Christ have put on Christ:</hi> So all that follow the Apostles and the true Church in their Succession, must be in the same Light, and Power, and Faith in Jesus Christ, which Jesus Christ hath been the Author of, and all must look to him for it, and so all Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren of God in this Faith, that brings them to have access to God, and Victory over that which sepa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rates from God.</p>
            <p>So all must succeed in this one Faith, and they that are baptized into Christ, must put him on; not make a Profession of him without them, and not put him on; if they do, they do not follow the Apostle, and the true Church, in their Succession.</p>
            <p>And the Apostle saith, <hi>Gal.</hi> 4. <hi>Because ye are Sons, God hath sent forth the Spirit of his Son into your Hearts, crying Abba Father:</hi> mark, into your Hearts: Now all that do succeed the Apostle and true Church here, it must be in the same Power and Spirit; they were in, that they may cry <hi>Abba</hi> Father: And the Apostle in <hi>Gal.</hi> 5. saith, <hi>walk in the Spirit and ye shall not fulfil the Lusts of the Flesh:</hi> and again he saith, <hi>If we live in the Spirit, let us also walk in the Spirit;</hi> mark, us the Apostles and the true Church, the true Christians: Now if ye do not walk in the same Spirit as the Apostles and true Church were in, then ye do not succeed the Apostles and true Church in their Succession, and Ordination, &amp; Possession that they were in; but do fulfil the Lusts of your Flesh: Now the Apostle saith, <hi>The Fruits of the Spirit are Love, Joy, Peace, Meekness, Long-suffering,
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:47377:14"/>Temperance, &amp;c. against which there is no Law, &amp;c.</hi> Now if you do not walk in the Spirit, you do not succeed the Apostles in their Ordination by the Spirit, neither do you succeed them in the Fruits of the Spirit; but are in the Fruits of the Flesh A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dultery, Fornication, Uncleanness, Laciviousness, Idolatry, Witchcraft, Hatred, Variance, Emu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation, Wrath, Strife, Sedition, Heresie, Envyings, Murders, Drunkenness, Revilings, and such like. And the Apostle tells you plainly, that they that do such things shall not inherit the Kingdom of God, and therefore, look all Christendom at your Fruits, and see whom you do succeed: And the Apostle saith, <hi>Gal.</hi> 6. <hi>For he that soweth to the Flesh shall of the Flesh reap Corruption; but he that soweth to the Spirit shall of the Spirit reap Life Everlasting.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now no Man can sow to the Spirit; but such as be in the same Spirit of God and Christ, that the Apostles were in, and they that be not in the same Spirit, that they were in, are not their Succeeding Seeds-Men in their Ordination by the holy Ghost, then such sow to the Flesh, and of the Flesh they reap Corruptions, and not everlasting Life; mark this all you Seeds-men what a Crop you may reap of Corruptions, that are sown to the Flesh, who have not sown in the same Power and holy Spirit as the Apostles sowed withal, and to: And the Apostle speaking to the <hi>Ephesians</hi> of his Knowledge in the Mystery of Christ, which in other ages was not made known unto the Sons of Men, as it is now reavaled unto his holy Apostles and Prophets, by the Spirit: Now you that do not succeed the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:47377:15"/>in this Spirit of revelation, you do not know the Mystery of Christ as the holy Prophets and Apostles did, though you may have the Form: And the Apostle saith in <hi>Ephes.</hi> 2.18. <hi>For through him we both have an access by one Spirit to the Father, and in whom ye also are built together an Habitation for God, through the Spirit.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>So all you that do follow the Apostles and the true Church in their Succession, it must be in the same Spirit of Intercession, that gives access to the Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, and by the same Spirit built together for an Habitation of God.</p>
            <p>And all you that deny having the same Spirit the Apostles had, how can you be built toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther an Habitation for God, or have access to the Father: And the Apostle saith, <hi>Finally, my Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren be strong in the Lord and in the Power of his Might; put on the whole Armour of God, that ye may be able to stand against the Wiles of the Devil; for we wrestle not against Flesh and Blood, but against Princi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>palities and Rulers of Darkness, &amp;c. And take unto you the Helmet of Salvation, and Sword of the Spirit, which is the Word of God.</hi> And now mark, they that follow the Apostles in their Succession and Ordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion in the true Church, they must be in the same <hi>Power and Might,</hi> and the same <hi>Helmet of Salvation,</hi> and <hi>Shield of Faith,</hi> and their <hi>Feet must be shod with the same Gospel of Peace,</hi> and their <hi>Loins must be gir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded with the same Girdle of Truth,</hi> and the same <hi>Breastplate of Righteousness,</hi> and they must have the same <hi>Sword of the Spirit, which is the Word of God,</hi>
               <pb n="29" facs="tcp:47377:15"/>with which they must not <hi>wrestle with Flesh and Blood, but spiritual Wickedness, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now you that are not in the same Power of the same Spirit, nor the same Faith, Truth, Righte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ousness, Gospel, Salvation and Armour of God, you are not the Successors of the Apostles in their Weapons, in their armour, in their Wrestling, who wrestle with Flesh and Blood, neither are you able to stand against the Wiles of Satan: And the Apostle saith, 2 <hi>Cor.</hi> 10.4. <hi>We do not war after the Flesh; for the Weapons of our Warfare are not carnal, but spiritual, mighty through God to the plucking down of strong Holds, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now all that follow the Apostles in their Succes<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sion and Possession and Ordination, their Weapons must not be carnal, and they must not wrestle after the Flesh, if they do, they are no Ministers in the Succession of the Apostles in their War and their Weapons: And the Apostle saith, 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 12. <hi>For by one Spirit are we all baptized into one Body, whether we be</hi> Jews <hi>or</hi> Gentiles, <hi>whether bond or free, and have been all made to drink into one Spirit;</hi> mark, here is the one Baptism, and here is the one Spirit, and here is drinking into one Spirit through several Sorts of People; these followed the Apostles in their Succession; and therefore all that follows the Apostles in their Succession, must be baptized by the same Spirit, as the Apostles and true Church was baptized withal, and drink in the same Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit; and they that say, they have not the same Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit the Apostles had, cannot be baptized into the
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:47377:16"/>same Body they were baptized into, neither can they have the same Union, in drinking in the same Spirit they drunk in, though they may have the Letter, they cannot succeed them in their Baptism in the Spirit, and drinking in the Spirit, if they have it not, and do not look for it (to wit, the Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit) now adayes: and the Apostle saith, 1 <hi>Tim.</hi> 4. <hi>Be thou an Example of the Believers</hi> IN WORD [mark] IN CONVERSATION [mark] IN CHARITY [mark] IN SPIRIT [mark] IN FAITH <hi>and</hi> PURITY [mark] Now all the Succedeers of <hi>Timothy</hi> and the Apostle, must be in the same Example, in the same Word, in the same Conversation, Charity, Spirit, Faith and Purity; and they that are not in the same Spirit, they cannot be in the same Faith, Word, Conver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sation, Charity and Purity, and then such do not succeed the Apostles nor <hi>Timothy:</hi> and in 1 <hi>Pet.</hi> 2. <hi>Ye also as living Stones are built up a spiritual Houshold</hi> [mark, are built up] <hi>and an Holy Priesthood, to offer up spiritual Sacrifices, acceptable to God by Jesus Christ.</hi> Now all that follow the Apostles and the true Church in their Succession and Possession of the Spirit, they must be the spiritual Houshold and living Stones, offering up spiritual Sacrifices accep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>table to God by Jesus Christ. And you that say, you have not the same Spirit the Apostles had and the Church in the Primitive Times, you are not the Successors of the Apostles, and you cannot be the living Stones, nor spiritual House, nor an holy Priesthood, neither can you offer up spiritual Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crifices
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:47377:16"/>to God, acceptable through Jesus Christ, not being in the same Spirit the Apostles and true Church were in.</p>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Concerning the Succession in the Fellowship.</head>
               <p>
                  <hi>IF we say</hi> (saith the Apostle) <hi>that we have fellow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ship with him</hi> (to wit, Christ and God) <hi>and walk in Darkness, we lye, and do not the Truth; but if we walk in the Light, as he is in the Light, we have fellowship one with another, and the Blood of Jesus Christ cleanseth us from all Sin.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Now all that do succeed the Apostles and true Church in the Fellowship, it must be by walking in the Light, as he is in the Light; and there they shall know cleansing by the Blood of Christ; but all such as hate the Light of Christ, and call it of the Devil or an Idol, such do not succeed the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles and the true Church, though they may get the Form of Words, and say, they have Fellowship with him, but walking in the Darkness, and ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting the Light, the Apostle tells you, they lye and do not the Truth, as you may see in 1 <hi>John:</hi> and the Apostle saith, <hi>for your fellowship is in the Gospel,</hi> Ephes. 1.</p>
               <p>So all that follow the Apostles and true Church in their Succession, it must be in the same Gospel, the Power of God, and not in a Form of Godliness, and denying the Power of the Gospel, that is a de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nying a Succession in their Fellowship: and in ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:47377:17"/>Place he speaks of keeping the Unity of the Spirit, which is the Bond of Peace: So all that do not follow the Apostles and true Church in this U<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nity of the Spirit, they want the Bond of Peace, yea, the Bond of the Prince of Princes Peace, and they that do follow the Apostles and true Church, it must be in the same Spirit that they were in, and so in the same Unity and Bond of Peace.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>Concerning Singing and Praying in the Spirit in the Succession of the Apostles.</head>
               <p>THE Apostle saith, <hi>Ephes.</hi> 6.18. <hi>Praying al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wayes with all Prayer and Supplication in the Spirit:</hi> Now they must be in the same Spirit the Apostles and true Church were in, if they do suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed them in the Spirit of Prayer, or else is it not like the <hi>Pharisees</hi> Babling, and such as ask, and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive not? And the Apostle saith, <hi>Rom.</hi> 8. <hi>Likewise the Spirit helpeth our Infirmities; for we know not what we should pray for as we ought, but the Spirit it self makes Intercession for us, &amp;c.</hi> So all that do succeed the Apostles in their Prayer, it is not using a Company of Words, and making Prayers, but it must be in the same Spirit which helps the Infirmity, &amp; makes Intercession; for without this Spirit the Apostles were in, we know not what we should pray for as we ought; so therefore the Spirit is the Helper, and makes Intercession; and therefore they that have not the same Spirit the Apostles had, want the
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:47377:17"/>Helper that should make Intercession, and are not in the succession of the Apostles &amp; the true Church. And again the Apostle saith, 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 14. <hi>I will pray with the Spirit, and I will pray with the Understanding also; I will sing with the Spirit, and I will sing with the Understanding also, when thou blessest with the Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit, &amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And therefore all that do pray, and sing, and bless, and not in the same spirit the Apostles were in, and the true Church, they are not the succeeders of the <hi>Apostles</hi> in their spiritual praying, singing and bles<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sing, neither can they pray with the Understanding, nor sing, nor bless with the Understanding, as the <hi>Apostles</hi> and the true Church did, if they be not in the same spirit they were in that gave forth the scriptures. And the <hi>Apostle</hi> saith, <hi>Let the Word of God dwell in you in all Wisdom, &amp;c. teaching and admo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nishing one another in Psalms, and Hymns, and spiritual Songs, singing with Grace in your Hearts to the Lord,</hi> Col. 3.</p>
               <p>Now they that do succeed the <hi>Apostles</hi> in this teaching and admonishing in Psalms, Hymns and spiritual songs, they must succeed them in the Word of Christ dwelling in their Hearts, and in the same spirit, and same Grace in the Heart that the <hi>Apostle</hi> and true Church were in; for they cannot succeed them in the Letter, in the Form without the Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, in their Possession: And the Apostle bids them pray without ceasing, and quench not the Spirit, and despise not prophecying: and they that do de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spise prophecy, and quench the Spirit, do not fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low the Apostles in their Succession and Ordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion,
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:47377:18"/>and Comfort, and Edification; who say they may all prophesie one by one.</p>
               <p>And so all that grieves, and quencheth; and vex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth the Spirit of God, and rebelleth against his Spirit, and resisteth the holy Ghost, and hates the Light of Christ, doth not follow the Apostles in their Succession &amp; Possession: And the Apostle saith, <hi>But ye beloved, build up your selves in your most holy Faith, pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in the holy Ghost:</hi> So all that do succeed the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles &amp; the true Church in their praying, it must be in the holy Ghost, and succeed them in their build<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, it must be in their holy Faith, which Christ is the Author of, &amp; they that are not in thesame holy Ghost and Faith, do not succeed the Apostles in their Building, and in their Praying: And the A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>postle saith in 1 <hi>Thes.</hi> 2.10. <hi>Ye are witnesses and God also how holily, and justly, and unblameably we behaved our selves among you that believe:</hi> so they that do suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed the Apostles, must succeed them, in that holy and just, and unblameable Life: and Christ saith in <hi>John</hi> 1. <hi>They that worship the Father must worship him in Spirit and Truth:</hi> Now none can succeed the Apostles in this Worship that Christ set up above sixteen hundred Years since; but who are in the same Spirit and Truth the Devil is out off, that the Apostles were in: and so it is clear; all that do succeed the Apostles in their Succession and Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dination, and Possession, it must be in the same Power and Spirit: And saith the Lord, <hi>I have or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dained thee a Prophet to the Nations, before I formed thee in the Belly I knew thee. Jer.</hi> 15. And a Multi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tude of the like Things concerning the Succession
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:47377:18"/>of the Apostles, and the true Church, of Sancti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fication, Justification, and Perfection and the like might be declared, and the Apostle saith, <hi>He that hath an Ear let him hear what the Spirit saith to the Churches:</hi> John speakes this seven Times in the <hi>Revelation;</hi> but if People have not the same Power and Spirit now adayes as the Apostles had, then they cannot hear what the Spirit saith. Now the Apostle saith, 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 14. <hi>If any thing be revealed to another that sits by, let the first hold his peace; for you may all prophesie one by one, that all may learn, and all may be comforted; for the Spirit of the Prophets is subject to the Prophets:</hi> Now all that deny Prophecy, and speaking one by one, deny the Way by which the Church may learn, and may be comforted, and deny the subjection of the Spirit of the Prophets, and such are not the succeeders in the same Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er and Spirit the Apostles were in: and the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stle saith, 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 14. <hi>Except ye utter by the Tongue, Words easie to be understood, how shall it be known what is spoken; for ye shall speak in the Air, therefore if I know not the Meaning of the Voice, I shall be unto him that speaketh is a</hi> Barbarian, <hi>and he shall be a</hi> Barba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rian <hi>unto me.</hi> And therefore all ye that speak, and preach, and pray in an unknown Tongue, or bless, the Apostle telleth you, ye are <hi>Barbarians,</hi> and speak to the Air, and so you do not follow him in his Succession; so therefore all that follow the Apostles and the true Church, in their Succes<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sion, Ordination and possession; either in preach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, praying, or singing, Fellowship, or Worship they must succeed them in the same Power and Spirit the Apostles were in.</p>
               <pb n="36" facs="tcp:47377:19"/>
               <p>And the Apostle saith, <hi>Gal.</hi> 6. <hi>As many desire to make fair shew in the Flesh,</hi> &amp; in <hi>Rom.</hi> 15.18. <hi>For I will not dare to speak of those Things, which Christ hath not wrought by me, to make the</hi> Gentiles <hi>obedient, by Word and Deed.</hi> Now consider, do you follow the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stle in this Succession, dare you speak of Things; which Christ hath not wrought by you, and to bring People to be obedient by Word or Deed? And is not this to make a fair shew in the Flesh of that which Christ hath not wrought by you? then you are not Succeeders to the Apostle and true Church: And the Apostle saith in 2 <hi>Cor.</hi> 10.15. <hi>Not boasting of Things without our Measure,</hi> that is, of other Mens Labours, &amp;c. <hi>but according to the Measure of the Rule, which God hath distributed unto us, &amp;c.</hi> Now consider do any follow the Apostles in their Succession; but who follow them in the Rule to wit of the Spirit? And do such follow the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles in their Rule, that boasts of other Mens La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bours, to wit the Prophets, Christ's and the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles Words, &amp; deny their Rule of the Spirit? &amp; did not the <hi>Corinthians</hi> make a great profession of Christ, and look't upon themselves to be great gifted-men? and did not the Apostle tell them, they were Reprobates if Christ were not in them, for all they might make a Profession of Christ without them? And so, is it not needful, for all Christians to try themselves, whether they be in the Faith, and prove, and know their own selves, that Christ is in them, except they be Reprobates; and so Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>probates may <hi>make</hi> a Profession of Christ without them, which do not follow the Apostles in their succession, who preach'd Christ within, the Hope
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:47377:19"/>of Glory, who said, <hi>The Life that I now live in the Flesh, is by the Faith of the Son of God, and I live, yet not I, but Christ that liveth in me,</hi> Gal. 2.20.</p>
               <p>So now who follow the <hi>Apostles</hi> in this their Pos<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>session, succession and Ordination, must follow them in the Possession of this Faith of the son of God, and in this Life in him: and the <hi>Apostle</hi> saith in <hi>Gal.</hi> 4.9, 10. <hi>But now after that ye have known God, or rather, are known of God, how turn you again to the weak and beggarly Elements, whereunto ye desire again to be in Bondage, ye observe Dayes and Moneths and Times, and Years, I am afraid of you, lest I have bestowed upon you Labour in vain.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Now consider this you that observe Dayes, Months, Times &amp; Years, which he calls beggarly Elements, and Bondage upon such that went into such Things, he was afraid he had bestowed his Labour in vain. Now you that do observe these Things, and follow these things the <hi>Apostle</hi> reproves, do not you succeed them that went into Bondage, and are not succeeders to the <hi>Apostles</hi> nor true Church: and in 1 <hi>Joh.</hi> 5.12.20. <hi>He that hath the Son hath Life, and he that hath not the Son hath not Life, and we know that the Son of God is come, and hath given to us an Understanding, that we may know him that is true, and we are in him that is true, even in his Son Jesus Christ, this is the true God and eternal Life.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Now here you may see their Possession, and what the <hi>Apostles</hi> and the Saints did possess, and they did confess Christ was come without them and within them, and they were in him: So all that follow the <hi>Apostles</hi> and true Church in their Possession and
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:47377:20"/>Succession, must have this Confession, that Christ is come, and hath given them an Understanding, and to be in them, and to have the Son if they have Life, signifying that all the Professors of the Son of God, if they have not the Son of God, they have not Life, then they cannot succeed the <hi>Apostles</hi> and the true Church in the same Life, Possession and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fession from the same Faith, and so are no true Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesses.</p>
               <p>Now who follow the <hi>Apostles</hi> in the Succession and Ordination, are faithful Witnesses; and in <hi>Luke</hi> 24.48. Christ sayes to his Disciples, <hi>Ye are Witnesses of these Things;</hi> and <hi>Acts</hi> 1.8. <hi>But ye shall receive Power after the Holy Ghost is come upon you, and ye shall be Witnesses unto me in all</hi> Judea, <hi>and</hi> Jerusa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lem, <hi>and</hi> Samaria, <hi>and to the utmost Parts of the Earth.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Now mark, these were the faithful and true Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesses in the Power and Holy Ghost that witnessed in <hi>Judea, Jerusalem</hi> and <hi>Samaria,</hi> and to the utmost parts of the Earth, to Christ: Nor can any suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed the <hi>Apostles,</hi> and be true Witnesses, but in the same Power and Holy Ghost; and in <hi>Acts</hi> 2.32, 33. <hi>This Jesus hath God raised up, whereof we all are Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesses; therefore being by the right Hand of God exalt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and having received of the Father the Promise of the Holy Ghost, he hath shed forth this which we now see and hear, &amp;c.</hi> and in <hi>Acts</hi> 3.15. <hi>Ye have killed the Prince of Life, whom God hath raised from the Dead, whereof we are Witnesses;</hi> now all these were Faithful Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesses: and <hi>Acts</hi> 5.32. <hi>We are his Witnesses of these Things</hi> (to wit, Christ) <hi>and so is also the Holy Ghost, whom God hath given to them that obey him:</hi> Mark
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:47377:20"/>then, those that do disobey God and Christ, receive not this Holy Ghost, and then they cannot succeed the Apostles in the same Holy Ghost, as faithful Witnesses of Christ. And <hi>Acts</hi> 10.39. <hi>We are Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesses of these things which he did</hi> (to wit, Christ) <hi>both in the Land of the</hi> Jews <hi>and at</hi> Jerusalem, <hi>whom they slew and hanged on a Tree, &amp;c.</hi> And <hi>Acts</hi> 13.30. <hi>But God hath raised him from the Dead, and he was seen many Dayes of them which came up with him from</hi> Ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lilee <hi>unto</hi> Jerusalem, <hi>and we are his Witnesses unto the People, and we declare unto you glad Tidings.</hi> And <hi>Acts</hi> 20.23. <hi>Save that the holy Ghost witnesseth in every City, saying, that Bonds and Afflictions abide me</hi> (to wit, him that preach'd Christ.) And <hi>Acts</hi> 26.22. <hi>Ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving therefore obtained Help from God, I continue unto this Day, witnessing both unto small and great, saying no other things then those which the Prophets and</hi> Moses <hi>did say should come, that Christ should suffer and rise from the Dead; and should shew Light unto the</hi> Gentiles.</p>
               <p>Now here you may see his faithful Witnesses in the Holy Ghost, witnessed to all, small or great, freely; and you that deny having the Holy Ghost the Apostles were in, and the Light of Christ, which he enlightens every one that comes into the World withal, which he shews to the People and to the <hi>Gentiles,</hi> you are no true Witnesses nor Succeeders to the Apostles, that call his Light (that he hath shewed to us <hi>Gentiles,</hi> which shines in our Hearts, to give us the Knowledge of the Glory of God in the Face of Christ Jesus) of the Devil, and the <hi>Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kers</hi> new Christ, and natural; you are no Succeed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers of the Apostles in the Power, Light and Spirit,
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:47377:21"/>nor true Witnesses, but their Opposers. And the Apostle saith, 1 <hi>Thes.</hi> 2.10. <hi>Ye are Witnesses and God also, how holily, justly and unblamably we behaved our selves amongst you that believed.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Now we cannot witness that you walk so holily, Justly and Unblamably in Christ, we who are the true Believers: And can you say, that God is your Witness of your Holy, Just and Unblamable Life, as the Apostles did? and if you cannot, you do not succeed them in their Possession and Succession; and the Apostle saying before, <hi>That the holy Ghost wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nessed in every City, saying, Bonds and Afflictions abide me.</hi> Now you that do persecute, and afflict, and bring into your Bonds and Prisons, and say, you have not the same Holy Ghost the Apostles had, and yet afflict them that be in the Holy Ghost, you are not the Succeeders of the Apostles in their Ordina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion and Succession. And the Apostle saith, 1 <hi>Tim.</hi> 4.14. <hi>Neglect not the Gift that is in thee, &amp;c.</hi> and he was to <hi>hold the Faith in a good Conscience,</hi> 1 Tim. 1.19. and he calls him <hi>his Son in the Faith,</hi> 1 Tim. 1.2. And in 1 Tim. 6.11, 12. <hi>But thou, O Man of God, follow Righteousness, Godliness and Faith, Love, Patience, Meekness; fight the good Fight of Faith, lay hold on Eternal Life, whereunto thou art also called, and hast professed a good Profession before many VVitnesses; and hold fast the form of sound VVords, which thou hast heard of me in Faith and Love, which is in Christ Jesus</hi> [mark] <hi>in Faith he had heard</hi> and in Love, which is in Christ Jesus; this Form of sound Words he was to hold fast, which he had heard in Faith, &amp;c. which Christ is the Author of, 2 <hi>Tim.</hi> 1.13. So they that
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:47377:21"/>be not in the same sound Words, which is heard in Faith and Love in Christ Jesus, do not succeed the <hi>Apostles</hi> in their Possession nor Ordination: and in 2 <hi>Tim.</hi> 1.14. <hi>That good thing which was committed un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to thee, keep by the holy Ghost, which dwelleth in us;</hi> [mark] Keep by the Holy Ghost which dwelleth in us: and in 2 Tim. 2.2. <hi>And all the things thou hast heard of me amongst many VVitnesses, the same commit thou unto faithful Men, who shall be able to teach others also.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Now mark, these followed the <hi>Apostles</hi> in the Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cession in the Holy Ghost, in the Faith in the good Things, which they dwelt in and committed unto faithful Men, which Mystery of the Faith is held in a pure Conscience; so none can succeed the <hi>Apostle</hi> nor <hi>Timothy,</hi> nor these faithful men, but in the same Faith, and in the same Gift of Prophecy, and in the good Thing, kept by the Holy Ghost dwelling in them: Now they that be not in the same Faith and Holy Ghost, and in the same good Thing the <hi>Apostle Timothy</hi> and those faithful men were in, do not suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed the <hi>Apostles</hi> and them, though they get the Form of Godliness; and the <hi>Apostle</hi> and <hi>Timothy</hi> did not commit those Things to faithful men, to teach them, and make a Trade of them; for they that do make a Trade of them are unfaithful men, and do not succeed the <hi>Apostles</hi> and <hi>Timothy,</hi> but are Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeders of such as resist the Holy Ghost, and Diso<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beyers of God; for the <hi>Apostle</hi> saith, <hi>He gives the holy Ghost to them that obey him:</hi> and the <hi>Apostle</hi> saith, 2 Tim. 3.5. <hi>Having a Form of Godliness, but denying the Power thereof, from such turn away:</hi> Now to have
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:47377:22"/>a Form of Christ's Words, the <hi>Apostles</hi> Words, or <hi>Timothy</hi>'s Words, or these faithful mens Words, and deny the Power and the holy Ghost that led them to speak them forth, they are to be turned away from, and are no Succeeders of the <hi>Apostles:</hi> and the <hi>Apostle</hi> saith, <hi>Heb.</hi> 12. <hi>VVherefore seeing we also are compassed about with so great a Cloud of VVit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesses, let us lay aside every VVeight, and the Sin that doth so easily beset us, and let us run with Patience the Race that is set before us, looking unto Jesus, the Author and Finisher of our Faith, &amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>So you may see it is not any man, nor Writings, nor Words, that is the author of Peoples Faith, but Jesus Christ, and all must look unto him, the author and Finisher of their Faith for it, if they do succeed this Cloud of Witnesses, which Faith is the Gift of God, and brings to have access to God, in which God is pleased: and the <hi>Apostle</hi> saith, 1 Joh. <hi>That which was from the beginning</hi> (mark, the Beginning, to wit, Christ) <hi>which we have heard</hi> (mark, they have heard that which was from the Beginning) <hi>which we have seen with our Eyes</hi> (mark, they had seen with their Eyes that which was from the Beginning <hi>(which we have lookt upon, and our Hands have handled of the Word of Life, which was from the beginning; for the Life was manifest, and we have seen it, and bear Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness, and shew it unto you, that Eternal Life which was with the Father, and was manifest unto us, that which we have seen and heard declare we unto you, that ye</hi> (to wit, the Church) <hi>also may have Fellowship with us, who had seen, heard, lookt upon and handled the Word of Life, and truly our Fellowship is with the Father and
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:47377:22"/>with the Son Jesus Christ; and these things I write unto you, that your Joy may be full.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And now mark, he that hath not the Son hath not Life, and he that hath the Son hath Life; and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore consider all ye Teachers and Churches in <hi>Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stendom,</hi> where is your Fellowship? have you heard that which was from the Beginning? have you seen, lookt upon and handled, and so bear Witness to what you have seen, heard and handled? and do you declare that to your Churches which you have heard, seen and handled, as the <hi>Apostles</hi> did? If not, you do not succeed the <hi>Apostles</hi> in their hearing, in their handling, in their looking, and seeing, and witnessing, and declaring to others: For will not the VVorldlings Reason teach you in your common Courts, that if a Company of VVitnesses come to bear VVitness before a Judge, the Judge asketh them whether they have seen, heard or lookt upon the man; if they say, No, they never heard, nor lookt upon him, nor do not expect ever to see him while on this side the Grave; what do you think the Judge will say to these VVitnesses, that will come to witness for or against a man they have ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver seen, nor heard, nor lookt upon, nor never expect to see him: But you may say, the VVitnesses heard others say so of him; and will this please the Judge? let worldly Reason Judge: So consider, if you ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver heard God's Voice, nor see his shape, as you may see in <hi>John</hi> 5. Christ the Judge did not accept of such as the <hi>Jews,</hi> that were sayers of what the Prophets and <hi>Moses</hi> said and did; for saith he, <hi>the Father himself, which hath sent me beareth Witness of
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:47377:23"/>me, but ye have neither heard his Voice at any time, nor seen his Shape;</hi> then these were not nor are not the true or faithful Witnesses of God nor Christ. And in <hi>Jer.</hi> 23.21. <hi>I have not sent these Prophets, yet they ran, I have not spoken to them, yet they prophesie;</hi> and Ver. 30, 31. <hi>Therefore behold I am against the Prophets, saith the Lord, that steal my Words every one from his Neighbour: Behold I am against the Prophets, saith the Lord, that use their Tongues, and say, he saith it;</hi> and Ver. 16. <hi>Thus saith the Lord of Hosts, hearken not unto the Prophets, nor unto the Words of the Prophets that prophesie unto you, they make you vain, they speak a Vision of their own Heart, and not from the Mouth of the Lord:</hi> And in Ezek. 13. <hi>Wo unto the Prophets that follow their own Spirit, and that see nothing, I have not sent them, saith the Lord, and they say, the Lord saith it, albeit I have not spoken to them▪ I am against you, saith the Lord, because with Lyes you make the Hearts of the Righteous sad, whom I have not made sad, &amp;c. I will deliver my People out of your Hand, and you shall know that I am the Lord, &amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And now consider these were not the Succeeders of the true Prophets, though they us'd their Tongues, and spoak, and ran with a Divination of their own Brains &amp; Studies, the Lord was against such, though they might say, thus saith the Lord, and get the Words of their Neighbour Prophets.</p>
               <p>So though you may say, thus saith Christ, and thus say the Apostles, and be such as run and God never sends nor Christ, &amp; have neither heard God's Voice, nor seen his Shape, and the Lord nor Christ have not spoken to you, and say, you have not the
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:47377:23"/>Holy Ghost as the Apostles had, and so follow your own Spirits, &amp; see nothing; and do not all, who say, they have not the same Spirit the Apostles had, fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low their own Spirits, and see nothing, and so are Succeeders of these false Prophets which God re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proved, and not the true Prophets nor Apostles? <hi>And how can you preach, except you be sent?</hi> saith the Apostle; for whom Christ sends they be in the Holy Ghost, and none can call him Lord, but by the Holy Ghost.</p>
               <p>And Christ saith, <hi>That he may abide with you for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever, to wit, the Comforter, the Holy Ghost,</hi> Joh. 14.16. <hi>even the Spirit of truth that shall lead you into all truth,</hi> and he should dwell in them, and should be with them; and also Christ saith, <hi>He would be with them and in them to the End of the World.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And now therefore how can you be faithful Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesses to God and Christ the Judge, by using your Tongues, and saying, he saith it, or by getting the Form of Godliness, and denying the Power and the Holy Ghost, to wit, the VVitness; and by your running and God never sent you, and though you say, he saith it, and hath never spoken to you; yea, though you may be Ministers of the Letter from <hi>Genesis</hi> to <hi>Revelations,</hi> and say, he or they say it, and yet never hear his Voice, nor see his Shape at any Time; then how at any Time can you be true VVitnesses, except you were in the same Power and Holy Ghost the Prophets and the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles were in?</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>He that hath the Son of God, hath Life, and he that
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:47377:24"/>hath not the Son of God, hath not Life;</hi> then how can he be a VVitness of the Life that he hath not seen, heard nor handled? and if Christ be not in him, he is a Reprobate, and then how can Reprobates be faithful VVitnesses of him, though they may talk of him by the Letter <hi>he is come,</hi> as the <hi>Jews</hi> by the Letter talkt <hi>he was to come?</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And therefore they that have the Son of God they have Life, they see it, they hear it, they handle it, they look upon it, that Life that was in the Begin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning, and can say, <hi>the Son of God is come, and hath given us an Understanding, and we know him that is true, and we are in him that is true,</hi> and so are faith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful VVitnesses, Succeeders of the Apostles and the true Church, and can declare what their Eyes have seen, and their Hands have handled, and what they have heard, and what they have looked upon, and bear witness and shew to others that Eternal Life, which was with the Father, and manifest unto us and in us, and can both witness and declare this to others freely, as they have received freely from God, that others may have Fellowship with them, and can say truly, <hi>Our Fellowship is with the Father and with the Son,</hi> and this we declare and witness to: I say, all that succeed the Apostles and the true Church, it must be in this Hearing, Sight, Hand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, VVitnessing and Declaring of this Possession of this Life, Christ that was in the Apostles and the true Church, else they are no Succeeders to them, nor in their Possession: For all the false Wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesses against the Prophets, Christ and the Apostles,
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:47377:24"/>they might profess the Scriptures; and the Beast, Whore, Anti-christ, Satan's Messengers and false Apostles, they might profess Christ in Words; but they that <hi>have him not, have not Life,</hi> and so are no true Hearers, Seers, Witnesses nor Succeeders, neither can they call Jesus Lord, except they be in the Holy Ghost the Apostles were in, neither can they witness as they did without the Holy Ghost, neither can they build up one another, except they be in the same Holy Ghost the Apostles and true Church were in, praying in the Holy Ghost, build<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing up one another in the most Holy Faith.</p>
               <p>So all true Succession is in this building in the Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly Ghost and Holy Faith that they were in; and if they be not in this, they are Pluckers down, and Scatterers from the Head, Lo here, lo there, lo there Christ without them, and not within them, and so no Succeeders to the Apostles, nor true Church, but to such, against whom the Cry is, Lo here, lo there, which Christ commands not to follow.</p>
               <p>And in 2 Cor. 2.17. <hi>For we are not as many which corrupt the Word of God, but as of Sincerity, but as of God in the Sight of God speak we in Christ.</hi> And in 2 Pet. 2.3. <hi>And through Covetousness shall they with feigned Words make Merchandize of you, &amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Now consider, such as these did not follow the Apostles in their Succession nor Ordination, nor any that be in feigned Words, who through Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vetousness make Merchandize of God's, Christ's, the Prophets and the Apostles Words, and of People.</p>
               <pb n="48" facs="tcp:47377:25"/>
               <p>And none follow the Apostles in their Succession and Ordination, but such as be of God, and in the Sight of God speak the Truth in Sincerity in Christ Jesus.</p>
               <p>So all they that teach for <hi>filthy Lucre, and serve not the Lord Jesus Christ, but their own Bellies, and by good Words and fair Speeches deceive the Hearts of the simple,</hi> Rom. 6.8. all such follow not the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stles and true Church in their Succession, but are reproved by them.</p>
               <p>And in Numb. 28. You may see how God or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dained his Law in Mount <hi>Sinai,</hi> and that his Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple should walk in it, which Law commanded their Offerings and the Priests to offer and attend upon their Servicce.</p>
               <p>But Christ Jesus, who ends the Law and the Offerings, and the Priests, by offering up him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>self once for all, he ordained his Disciples to preach, and commands them, FREELY as they had received of him, so FREELY to give.</p>
               <p>And therefore they that follow the Apostles in their Ordination and in their Succession, must give FREELY, as they have received FREELY.</p>
               <p>And Christ commands his Disciples <hi>Not to Swear AT ALL,</hi> but keep to <hi>YEA</hi> and <hi>NAY</hi> in their Communication, and to bless, and curse not.</p>
               <p>And the Apostle that kept in the Ordination
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:47377:25"/>of Christ and his Command, forbad Swearing and Cursing, and set up Yea and Nay, as Christ commanded.</p>
               <p>Now all them that swear and curse, do not fol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low the Apostles in their Succession nor Ordination nor Qualification.</p>
               <p>And Christ forbids his Ministers for being cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led <hi>GRACIOUS LORDS,</hi> as the <hi>Gentiles</hi> were, or for being called of Men <hi>MASTER,</hi> as the <hi>Pharisees</hi> were.</p>
               <p>And therefore they that follow the Apostles in Christ's Ordination, and in the Succession of the Apostles, must keep his Commands; for such Ministers that do plead for such Titles, and to be called of Men <hi>MASTERS</hi> and <hi>GRACI<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>OUS LORDS,</hi> succeed the <hi>Pharisees</hi> and the <hi>Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiles,</hi> and not Christ nor the Apostles.</p>
               <p>And therefore none can succeed the Apostles, but in the same Power of God and Holy Ghost that they were in, who gave forth the Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures, and they must receive Christ, and live in him, who is the ROCK OF AGES, and so to know him to be with them and in them to the End of their Age, and so to the End of the World, who is the ROCK and FOUN<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>DATION of all the Righteous in their A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges; and they that do succeed the Apostles, must succeed them in their Work and Foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dation.</p>
               <pb n="50" facs="tcp:47377:26"/>
               <p>So in the Light, in the Life, and in the Power of Christ Jesus, and in him, and he in them, who is the first and last; here is all the true Succession and Succeeders, who walk and live in Christ Jesus, and he in them, who is first and last.</p>
               <closer>
                  <dateline>Swarthmore, <date>
                        <hi>the</hi> 10th <hi>of the</hi> 9th <hi>Month,</hi> 1675.</date>
                  </dateline>
                  <signed>G. Fox.</signed>
               </closer>
               <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
               <pb facs="tcp:47377:26"/>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>